Guide to the Kenneth M. Reardon papers, 1971-2015.
Reardon, Kenneth M. papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Kenneth M. Reardon papers, 1971-2015.
8528
Reardon, Ken,
16.5 cubic feet.
Reports, course materials, printed materials, publications, research materials, and correspondence.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection consists of Kenneth M. Reardon's professional papers, including correspondence, teaching materials, and community plans and studies.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Kenneth M. Reardon is a professor of city planning specializing in neighborhood and community planning. He received his B.A. in Sociology from the University of Massachusetts Amherst in 1976, a Master of Urban Planning from Hunter College of the City University of New York in 1982, and a Ph.D. in City and Regional Planning from Cornell University in 1990. From 1990 to 1999, Reardon served on the planning faculty at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign, where his work in establishing the East St. Louis Action Research Project earned him the AICP President's Award and the Dale Prize for Excellence in City Planning. He then taught and was chair of the Department of City and Regional Planning at Cornell University from 1999-2008, pursuing research, teaching, and outreach in the areas of neighborhood planning, community development, and community/university development partnerships. During his time in Ithaca, he coordinated the department's New Orleans Planning Initiative, which produced a recovery plan for the Ninth Ward. From 2008 to 2015, he served as director of the graduate program for the Department of City and Regional Planning at the University of Memphis, where he coordinated two resident-led economic and community development planning efforts in South Memphis. Since 2015, Reardon has been professor and director of the master's program in Urban Planning and Community Development at the University of Massachusetts Boston.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection consists of Kenneth M. Reardon's professional papers, including correspondence, teaching materials, and community plans and studies.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Reardon, Ken, 1953-
Subjects:
City planning.; Neighborhood planning.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical and Early Career
Box 1
Series II. Course Materials
Boxes 1-3; 14-16
Graduate Student Teaching, 1984-1990
University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, 1990-1999
Cornell University, 1999-2008
Series III. Conferences and Consulting
Boxes 3-4; 16
Planners Network Conferences
Other Conferences
Consulting: Community Plans, Papers, Grants, and Studies
General
Annie E. Casey Foundation
Ford Foundation
Series IV. Major Projects
Boxes 1-14; 16-17
Cornell Field Study, 1984-1990
University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign: East St. Louis Project, 1990 - 1999
Cornell University
New Orleans Planning Initiative (NOPI)
Liberty Economic Action Project (LEAP)
Northside, Ithaca
Press
Cornell Engaged Scholars and Urban Scholars Program (CUSP)
University of Memphis
South Memphis
Brownsville
Vance and the Green Machine
General Memphis
Series V. Articles, Speeches, Lectures, Awards
Boxes 14-15
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical and Early Career
  - Donald G. Sullivan memorial, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Green Point Neighborhood Preservation study (Hunter), June 1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Sullivan: Workshops and Neighborhood Planning, 1980 - 1987 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Cornell Acceptance Letter - Admission to MCRP program, March 9, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - AICP Reading Test, 1982 - 1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Also includes unofficial Cornell transcript for spring 1983
  - Letter of Recommendation to Rutgers, January 1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memo - Ph.D. Career Objectives, February 7, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Ken Reardon - Student Writings, Cornell, Fall 1982 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - ACP Press, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Chicago: State of Metro Economy, Class Notes, 1984 - 1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Economic Development in Boston and Chicago, October 1986 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Washington Administrative Evaluation, August 14, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    A paper by Ken Reardon, presented to the 37th Annual Meeting of the Society for the Study of Social Problems
  - Correspondence: Community Organizing NJ senior citizens, October 1983 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Field Study Agency Correspondence, 1986 - 1989 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Student Correspondence Cornell Field Study, 1985 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Personal Correspondence Cornell Field Study, 1983 - 1996 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - CV and Statement for Ad-Hoc Review Committee, November 22, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Field Study. Certificates of Appreciation, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Feinberg Correspondence and Draft, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - NYC Field Study Correspondence, 1988 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Letter of Recommendation to University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign (UIUC), November 22, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - UIUC Correspondence, 1990 - 1998 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Election to Tenure, March 13, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Approval of Thesis/Dissertation, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Cornell University: Unified New Orleans Plan Correspondence, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - New Orleans Background Correspondence, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Cornell Correspondence, 2000 - 2008 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Personal Correspondence - Cornell, 2005 - 2012 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - University of Memphis Correspondence, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Cornell University: Employment Materials, 1987 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - UIUC Promotion to Associate Professor, June 1997 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - UIUC Granting Sabbatical Leave, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - UIUC COPC Grant, September 1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Champaign NIP (Neighborhood Improvement Plan) - Project Proposal, January 11, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Administration: UEMAP Proposal, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Administrative Correspondence: Cornell University Faculty Response to "Realignment", August 19, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Diversity Workshop, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Annual Reports, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - CRP Retreat, April 2004 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Graduate Research Fellows, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Public Service Proposal, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Social Justice C. program proposal, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Promotion from Associate Professor to Professor, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Cornell University: Congratulations on appointment to chair of CRP dept., August 20, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Cornell University: Chair to Dean correspondence, 2004 - 2006 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Cornell Employment, 2000 - 2008 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Faculty Review - Ken Reardon, March 2008 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Cornell University: Letter of Resignation, May 1, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - University of Memphis: City of Choice correspondence, March 2010 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - CRP Annual Program Review, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Correspondence: Safe Routes to Schools Contract, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Marie Curie Fellowship, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Faculty Chair Evaluation of Ken Reardon, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Faculty Correspondence, August 24, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - MPD Proposal, May 2009 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - University of Memphis Administrative Correspondence, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 56)
- Series II. Course Materials and Student Work
  - Graduate Student Teaching, 1984-1990
    - ID408 Ecology of Urban Organizations, Spring 1986 (Box 1, Folder 58)
    - Field Study I, September 15, 1988, Undated (Box 1, Folder 59)
    - Field Study II-III, 1984 - 1990 (Box 1, Folder 60-61)
    - Neighbourhood Organizing Drive ID408, June 25, 1986, Undated (Box 1, Folder 62)
    - Neighborhood Observation ID408, Spring 1987 (Box 1, Folder 63)
    - Coop Ed 111: Exploring the Workplace: An Experimental Place, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    - URB 787.60 Workshop in Neighborhood Preservation (Sullivan), Spring 1981 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - FISP 402 (Field and International Study Program), Fall 1987 (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Includes Essex Street Retail Market Project documents.
    - CEH/ FISP 402 (Field and International Study Program), Spring 1989 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign, 1990-1999
    - Urban Planning and Design Summer Program, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    - Urban Planning and Design Summer Program - Orientation Packet, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    - UP101: Planning in Cities and Regions
      - Test and Key Terms/Concepts, Fall 1994 (Box 1, Folder 67)
      - Readings, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 68)
      - Curriculum, Undated (Box 1, Folder 69)
      - Natural Industrial Package, Undated (Box 1, Folder 70)
      - Mercantile (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - Reaganomics, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - Regional Planning, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - Tests, October 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - Zoning, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - War on Poverty, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - Neighborhood Planning, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - Readings and In-Class Materials I-VI, c. 1991 - 1998 (Box 2, Folder 8-13)
      - Readings I & II, Fall 1995 (Box 15, Folder 18-19)
      - Readings, Fall 1998 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - UP199: Urban Development Seminar, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - UP374: Neighborhood Planning Workshop - Class Notes, 1964 - 1997 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - UP374: Neighborhood Planning Seminar I - Community Organizing I-II, 1995 - 1996, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16-17)
    - UP374: Neighborhood Planning Workshop, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Bond for Deed Community Development Workshop Class Material, 1992 - 1994, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19-20)
    - UP378: Community Development Workshop, Spring 1999 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - UP378: Community Development Workshop, 1998 - 1999 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - UP394D Organic Behavior, Fall 1998 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - UP394 Reading Materials. Reading Notes, 1998, Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - "Environmental Impact of Industrial Heavy Metal Contamination of Soil in East St. Louis, Illinois" by Michael David Kaminski., 1996 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Preliminary Research Proposal: Correspondence.
    - Master's Thesis: " Evaluating Manufactured Housing as a Development Tool for the City of East Saint Louis, Illinois" by Lawrence B. Weissman, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Emerson Park MetroLink Station by Cassandra Ecker, Master's Thesis, June 1998 (Box 3, Folder 13)
      A study of transit-oriented development around a new Metrolink Station in the Emerson Park neighborhood, inclusive of land use and zoning maps, case studies and recommendations; prepared for the Emerson Park Development Corporation
    - Alta Sita Neighborhood Planning and ESLARP by Janni Sorensen, June 22, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      Student work on the Alta Sita neighborhood revitalization and comprehensive planning process, the resident-led Alta Sita Neighborhood, Inc. impact in the neighborhood and the partnership with the East St. Louis Action Research Project (ESLARP).
    - Bond For Deed Community Development Workshop: Student Work, 1993 - 1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Student Drafts "The Deconstruction of East St. Louis: A Systematic Examination of Bond-for-Deed and its Role in Reshaping the City" by William V. Cork (1993, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Students drafts, "Installment Land Contracts in East St. Louis: Analysis and Solutions" by Workshop Members (1994), 1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - "Bond for Deed in East St. Louis, IL" by Denise Chaffee and Paul Foppe, 1993 - 1994 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Master's Project, "Code Enforcement in East St. Louis, Illinois" by Daniel A. Thomas, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Homebuyer's Guide, Everything you wanted to know about buying a home in East St Louis but were afraid to ask!, Undated (Box 3, Folder 17)
      Affordable Housing I class, George Haenisch, Jon Branham, Sajeet Maghera, Marissa Chutipisalkul
    - University- Community Partnership Power Disparities by Janni Sorensen, Ph.D., 2006 (Box 3, Folder 18)
      A dissertation on power disparities in the case of the longstanding university-community partnership between the university's East St. Louis Action Research Project and neighborhood based groups in East St. Louis; focuses on participatory planning process in terms of who participates, how participation takes place, and the outcomes of the planning processes.
    - "Designing Safe Neighborhoods" by Marcy Shure., 1996 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      Thesis. Landscape Architecture
    - UP374 Neighborhood Planning Workshop, Fall 1990 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - UP374 Neighborhood Planning Workshop, Spring 1991 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Summer Program, Urban Planning and Design, June 6 - August 2, 1991 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - UP199 Urban Ethnographies, May 1992 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - UP374 Neighborhood Planning Seminar, Spring 1992 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - UP378 Community Development Workshop, Fall 1994 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - UP378 Community Development Workshop, Spring 1996 (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - UP378 Neighborhood Planning Seminar, Spring 1997 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - UP374 Critical Theory, Spring 1997 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - UP374 Organization, 1999, Undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
      Includes projector slides from Neighborhood Planning and "Building Support for Your Plan/ The Rewards and Challenges of N[on] P[rofit]"
    - UP378 Community Development Workshop, Spring 1999 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Community Organizing, March 1999 - April 1999 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Course Materials, 1990, 1999, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Cornell University, 1999-2008
    - CRP318 - Politics of Community Development, Spring 2005 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - CRP330 / CRP530: Neighborhood Planning Workshop, Fall 2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - CRP330 / CRP530: Neighborhood Planning Workshop, Fall 2003 (Box 2, Folder 16)
      Reardon Community Development (Liberty)
    - CRP330 / CRP530: Neighborhood Planning Workshop, Fall 2006 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - CRP200: Contemporary Planning - "The Promise and Pitfall of Contemporary Planning", Fall 2003 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - CRP200: Contemporary Planning - Syllabus, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - CRP200: Contemporary Planning - Curriculum, Undated (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - CRP200: Contemporary Planning - Lectures, Undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - CRP200: Contemporary Planning - Reader, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - CRP200: Contemporary Planning - PowerPoints, 2004, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - CRP457: Community Service Workshop Syllabus, Fall 2000 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - CRP457: Community Service Learning, Fall 2007 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      Syllabus and Proposal for the Center for Research and Community Action
    - CRP457: Community Service Learning Reader, Undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - CRP479: Community Service Workshop, 2000 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      Syllabus and Ithaca Candidates' Forum 2000. Also CRP457
    - CRP649: Urban Design Syllabus, Fall 2006 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Special Topics: Neighborhood Stabilization Through Urban Food Security, Fall 2010 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      Syllabus and Course Material
    - Special Topics: Community Organization and Urban Policy Making in Planning, Fall 2009 (Box 3, Folder 7)
      Syllabus and Professional Practice Tour of New York City.
    - ESCI3451: Introduction to City and Regional Planning - "Contemporary Challenges and Opportunities" Syllabus, Spring 2011 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - CRP395 / CRP619: Community Development Workshop: Rochester CDC Initiative, 2001 - 2002 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      Syllabus and Rochester Orientation Trip Schedule.
    - CRP395 / CRP649: Urban Regeneration: London's Thames Gateway Project, Spring 2007 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      Syllabus, Readings, Sign-in sheet and more course material.
    - CRP200: The Promise and Pitfall of Contemporary Planning, 2006 (Box 3, Folder 20-27)
      Arts and Culture, Public Safety, Services and Utilities, Housing, Transport, Education/Youth, Economic Development, Environment
    - CRP330 / CRP530: Neighborhood Planning - Student Work, Fall 2006 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - Student Work: New Orleans, April 8, 2011, Undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
      New Orleans. Low-income housing restoration and Smart Growth Solutions.
    - Introduction to Planning - Interviews, Fall 2008 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      Minutes and notes from discussion.
    - Miscellaneous Course Materials, 1990, 1999, 2006 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - CRP619 Economic Development Planning, Fall 2000 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - CRP309/ CRP509 Community Development Seminar, Spring 2003 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - CRP200 I-III, Fall 2003 (Box 16, Folder 3-5)
    - CRP530 I & II, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 6-7)
    - CRP331 Community Development Workshop I & II, 2005 (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
    - CRP330 Neighborhood Planning, Fall 2006 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - CRP457 Reader I & II, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 11-12)
    - Community Development Seminar, 2008 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Cornell Course Evaluations for CRP200 and CRP330/ CRP530, Fall 2003 (Box 14, Folder 4)
- Series III. Conferences and Consulting
  - Planners Network Conferences
    - Linking Citizen Action & Equity Planning, State Community College. East St. Louis, Illinois., May 19 - May 21, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      Contains Booklet, Folders (Agenda, Schedule, Steering Committee Ballot, Maps, ESLARP), Correspondence, List of Participants, Registration, Workshops.
    - Press and Correspondence, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - Market - Press and Correspondence, 1995 - 1996 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - Planners Network Conference - List of Attendees, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - Planners Network Conference, University of Massachusetts, Lowell, June 17-20, 1999 (Box 3, Folder 35)
      Booklet, Agenda/ Schedule and Schedule Changes.
    - "Voices of Change: Lessons From Citizen Planners" Rochester, New York, June 21 - 24, 2001 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      Booklet, agenda, maps, organizing documents.
    - "New Visions for Historic Cities: Bridging Divides, Building Futures" Holyoke, Massachusetts, June 13 - 16, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 37)
      Conference Guide Booklet.
    - Promoting Economic Development through Regional Cooperation, Planning and Development, May 18 - 21, 2011 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      Invitations, Proposal, Host Committee Material, Budget, Planning Activities, Correspondence, Agenda, Notes, Registration Form and Promotional Material.
  - Other Conferences
    - Valley Peace Coalition Conference, February 8, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 39)
      Indochina Day. University of Massachusetts. Booklet of Programs and Agenda.
    - UIUC: Volunteer Action and Local Democracy: A Partnership for a Better Urban Future. Istanbul, UNRISD, May 27 - 30, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - UIA Barcelona, July 1996 (Box 3, Folder 41)
      Correspondence and research. "Looking at East St. Louis: Lessons from a city in Transition" by Kenneth M. Reardon, Michael J. Andrejasich, Kevin Hinders, Ernest Clay and Robert I. Selby. "Alternative Approaches to Community Empowerment in the St. Louis Metropolitan Region" by Kenneth M. Reardon.
    - U.S. Housing and Urban Development (H.U.D.) Community Outreach Partnership Centers (C.O.P.C) Conference and Evaluations, August - September 1998 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      Metropolitan Community College. East St. Louis, IL. Invitation, Flyers, Schedule, Speaker Notes, Evaluation Team Meeting
    - Campus Compact Conference, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Council of Independent Colleges (C.I.C.) Teaching and Learning Workshop, June 7 - 9, 200 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      Albany, NY. List of Potential Funding, Resource List, Workshop Materials, Copy of article in The Chronicle of Higher Education, "Point of View" by Ernest L. Boyer, Correspondence, bibliography.
    - Faculty Service Learning Symposium, 2000 - 2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      Ithaca's Neighborhood Based Planning Initiative. PowerPoint, projector sheets, educational material, informational material, resources.
    - Working Papers Series on Service Learning. Volume 3., 2000 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Public Service Center "Community Connection: A newsletter for Cornell Students Engaged in Service for Social Change" Nov- Dec 2001 Issue., 2000 - 2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Challenges of Service- Learning in Diverse Disciplines, 2000 - 2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Cornell Alumni in Public Service October 2001 Issue 6., 2000 - 2002 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - 18th Annual Planning and Zoning Institute, October 6, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 5)
      Includes correspondence.
    - Mid-South Planning and Zoning Institute, May 20, 2011, April 19, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 6)
      Building more Vibrant and Sustainable Communities Through Participatory Planning and Design.
    - TAPA Conference - Ethics, 2010 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - The Memphis Conversation on Evolutionary Theory and Quality of Life: Policy Implications for Building the Just City, November 5 - 7, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 8-9)
  - Consulting: Community Plans, Papers, and Studies
    - General
      - Community Power Structure Studies: A Review of Major Research Published 1959 - 1975. A paper presented to Professor Robert N. Stern by Kenneth Reardon., Spring 1984 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      - New Jersey Citizen Action Alliance. First Year Victories. Vol. I, No. II. It's time to Fight Back., Undated (Box 4, Folder 11)
      - New Jersey Federation of Senior Citizens, 1978 - 1982 (Box 4, Folder 12)
        Correspondence, Booklets, Advertisements, Informational Material. 3rd Annual Convention. Senior Power that Works ;5th Annual Convention. Dignity through Senior Power. Wildwood Convention Center A Shopper's Guide to Life and Health Insurance. "Unemployment offset rules changed" February 1981; Copies of news article.
      - New Jersey Federation - Directory and Memos, 1975 - 1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
        List of grants and contributions received between 1975- 1977. Leadership notes on the Federation Process. Organizational Needs. Projected Budget for 12 months October 1977- 1978. Assured Revenue October 1977- 1978
      - New Jersey Citizen Action Project Proposal, December 1, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 14)
      - Senior Justice Project, 1987 - 1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
        Correspondence. Research. United Senior Alliance. "The Future of Senior Power in New Jersey" by Kenneth Reardon. Census. News Article.
      - HANDs Consulting Correspondence, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 16)
        "Restoring Problem Properties to the Tax Rolls. Rehabilitation and Home ownership is the Answer to Neighborhood Stability" The Community Building Funding Pool of the Affordable Housing Network of New Jersey; Three Year Timeline for Problem Property Action Plan.
      - Campus Compact: Request, "Structuring the Reflection Process. Structuring the Communication", April 2003 (Box 4, Folder 17)
      - Campus Compact Contract, 2000- 2002 (Box 4, Folder 18)
        Campus Compact. Higher Education in Services to the Nation. Correspondence. Booklet "Notice of Funds Available. Requests for Proposals for Making a Civic Investment". Award Summary.
      - Indiana Campus Compact, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 19)
        Award Letter for University of Illinois. Universities as Citizen Institutional Development Grant.
      - Oakland, California, September 1, 1999 (Box 4, Folder 26)
        "No Substitute: An Urgent Call for Trained, Permanent Teachers in Oakland Schools" by Oakland Association of Community Organizations for Reform Now (ACORN) Small booklet of Woodland Elementary.
      - Contract, 1988 - 2003 (Box 4, Folder 27)